Walders, Joseph; Collection mss030
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Joseph Walders Papers
1949-1977
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
mss030
6.98 cubic ft.
This collection contains television and film scripts, movie posters, still photographs, lobby cards, and pressbooks collected by Joseph Walders.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
Items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives by Joseph Walders in 1989 and by Joni Browne-Walders, wife of Joseph Walders in 1992.
Biographical History
Joseph Walders (1948-1992) was a writer and television producer. He wrote and produced the science television news reports for the "Mr. Wizard's World" program on Nicelodeon for 11 years. He was the author of The World's Most Challegning TV Quiz (1977) and also wrote articles for TV Guide, Popular Science, and Science Digest.
Walders received his bachelor's degree in radio and teleivsion from Syracuse Unviersity in 1971. Born in Pennsylvania, he lived in Los Angeles for many years before moving to Troy, New York.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes 151 television and film scripts, many with shooting schedules, and hand-written revisions, deletions, and annotations, 1952-1977; and 46 movie posters, 78 still photographs, 39 lobby cards, and 4 pressbooks for 68 films, many of them produced by George Pal or directed by Alfred Hitchcock, 1952-1977, all collected by Joseph Walders. Emphasis is on science fiction, fantasy, adventure, light comedy, mystery, and intrigue. Alfred Hitchcock Presents, The Fugitive, I Spy, The Invaders, and Science Fiction Theatre comprise two-thirds of the scripts collected by Walders.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged into two series: Television and Film Scripts and Film Posters and Stills. Both are arranged alphabetically.
Literature; Television--Production and direction; Motion picture plays; Screenplays; shooting scripts; Photographs; Posters; Walders, Joseph (1948-1992); Hitchcock, Alfred, 1899-1980; Pal, George
- Television and Film Scripts, 1952-1977; 1; 3.44 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains television and film scripts from the 1950s, 1960s, and 1970s collected by Joseph Walders. The majority of scripts are from the television programs Alfred Hitchcock Presents, I Spy, and Science Fiction Theatre.
  - Alfred Hitchcock Hour, The: "Jar, The", 1963 October 10 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Alfred Hitchcock Presents: "Bull in a China Shop", 1957 December 10 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Alfred Hitchcock Presents: "Crackpot", 1956 August 31 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Alfred Hitchcock Presents: "Cream of the Jest, The", 1956 December 7 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Alfred Hitchcock Presents: "Crocodile Case, The", 1958 April 9 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Alfred Hitchcock Presents: "Dontt Interrupt", 1958 May 27 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Alfred Hitcicock Presents: "Mr. Blanchard's Secret", 1956 July 26 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Alfred Hitchcock Presents: "Mr. Cinderella", 1956 September 14 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Alfred Hitchcock Presents: "Nightmare in 4-D", 1956 August 27 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Alfred Hitchcock Presents: "Restless Corpse, The", 1957 February 27 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Alfred Hitchcock Presents: "Rose Garden, The", 1956 August 1 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Alfred Hitchcock Presents: "Three Dreams of Mr. Findlater, The", 1957 January 25 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bat Masterson: "Cattle and Canes", 1959 November 19 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Big Town: "Shoplifter, The", 1953 June 1 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Bob Newhart Show, The: "Birth of a Salesman", 1976 January 13 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Bob Newhart Show, The: "Bob's Change of Life", 1977 July 12 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Cannon: "Devil's Playground", 1971 October 24 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Captain Z-Ro: "Oxygen", 1953 August 15 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Case of the Dangerous Robin, The: "Man in the Shadows", 1961 February 9 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Cowboy in Africa: "Tomorrow on the Wind", 1967 September 7 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - "Daddy's Gone a-Hunting" - Feature Script, Undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Death Valley Days: "Bill Bottle's Birthday", Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Death Valley Days: "Death in the Desert", 1965 January 15 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Dial 999: "Barge Burglars", Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Doctor Christian: no title, 1956 October 10 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Family Affair: "Lesson for Grown-Ups", 1968 July 10 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Fay: "Not Another Mother's Day", Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Flipper: "Dolphins Don't Sleep Part One", 1966 April 19 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Fugitive, The: "Detour on a Road Going Nowhere", 1964 October 10 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Fugitive, The: "Homecoming, The", 1964 March 3 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Fugitive, The: "Just One Road I Travel", 1964 October 23 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Fugitive, The: "Middle of a Heat Wave", 1965 June 25 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Fugitive, The: "Nightmare at Northoak", 1963 September 23 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Fugitive, The: "Other Side of the Coin, The", 1966 October 17 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Fugitive, The: "Second Sight", 1966 May 25 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Gentle Ben: "How Wild Is Wild", 1968 July 26 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Goodbye Raggedy Ann" - TV Movie, 1971 June 30 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Gunsmoke: "Time of the Jackals", 1968 May 31 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Harrigan & Son: "Comeback, The", 1961 January 7 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Hawaii Five-O: "Samurai", 1968 May 15 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - I Spy: "American Princess, An", 1967 June 26 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - I Spy: "Anyplace I Hang Myself is Home", 1967 July 6 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - I Spy: "Beautiful Children, The", 1967 January 17 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - I Spy: "Casanova from Carnarsie", 1966 November 22 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - I Spy: "Child Out of Time", 1966 July 12 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - I Spy: "Child Out of Time", 1966 September 4 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - I Spy: "Choice, The", 1967 June 7 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - I Spy: "Conquest of Maude Murdock, The", 1965 October 21 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - I Spy: "Cops and Robbers", 1966 November 15 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - I Spy: "Crusade to Limbo", 1965 October 8 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - I Spy: "Day Called 4 Jaguar, A", 1965 October 22 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - I Spy: "Enchanted Cottage, The", 1966 August 10 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - I Spy: "Father Abraham", 1966 April 19 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - I Spy: "Few Miles West of Nowhere, A", 1967 March 21 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - I Spy: "Get Thee to a Nunnery", 1966 August 23 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - I Spy: "Gift from Alexander, A", 1966 March 28 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - I Spy: "Happy Birthday Everybody", 1967 June 12 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - I Spy: "Honorable Assassins", 1967 January 6 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - I Spy: "Laya", 1967 February 2 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - I Spy: "Lisa", 1966 February 25 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - I Spy: "Little Boy Lost", 1966 February 11 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - I Spy: "Lori", 1966 February 7 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - I Spy: "Lotus Eater, The", 1967 February 2 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - I Spy: "Medarra Block, The", 1967 February 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - I Spy: "My Mother The Spy", 1965 December 23 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - I Spy: "Name of the Game, The", 1967 July 7 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - I Spy: "Night Train To Madrid", 1966 December 13 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - I Spy: "Now You See Her ... Now You Don't", 1967 February 28 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - I Spy: "Oedipus at Colonus", 1967 February 6 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - I Spy: "One of Our Bombs Is Missing", 1966 April 18 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - I Spy: "One Thousand Fine", 1965 November 12 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - I Spy: "Philotimo", 1966 January 23 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - I Spy: "Pinwheel", 1967 June 7 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - I Spy: "Plains in Spain, The", 1966 August 15 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - I Spy: "Red Sash of Courage", 1967 February 27 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - I Spy: "Rome? Take Away Three", 1966 April 26 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - I Spy: "Room with a Rack", 1966 July 18 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - I Spy: "Seventh Captain, The", 1967 February 7 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - I Spy: "Shana", 1967 July 5 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - I Spy: Shooting schedules for various episodes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - I Spy: "So Coldly Sweet", 1966 January 28 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - I Spy: "Sophia", 1966 April 13 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - I Spy: "Spy Business, The", 1967 July 20 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - I Spy: "Suitable for Framing", 1967 March 21 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - I Spy: "Tag, You're It", 1967 July 14 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - I Spy: "There Was a Little Girl", 1966 January 10 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - I Spy: "This Guy Smith", 1967 March 20 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - I Spy: "To Florence with Love", 1966 March 22 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - I Spy: "Trial by Treehouse", 1966 February 25 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - I Spy: "Trouble with Temple, The", 1966 July 12 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - I Spy: "Trouble with Temple, The", 1966 September 1 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - I Spy: "Turkish Delight", 1965 December 28 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - I Spy: "Turnabout for Traitors", 1967 August 24 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - I Spy: "You Can't Shoot an Honest Man", 1967 February 28 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Invaders, The: "Attack", 1967 May 31 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Invaders, The: "Attack", 1967 June 6 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Invaders, The: "Dark Outpost", 1967 August 2 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Invaders, The: "Enemy, The", 1967 May (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Invaders, The: "Explosion of Truth" - Chapter Four, 1965 June 25 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Invaders, The: "Innocent, The", 1967 January 13 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Invaders, The: "Labyrinth", 1967 August 29 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Invaders, The: "Spores, The", 1967 July 12 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Invaders, The: "Task Force", 1967 October 16 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Ironside: "Little Jerry Jessup", 1969 December 10 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - It's a Man's World: "Beavers and the Otters, The", 1962 February 8 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - It's About Time: "King Hec", 1966 October 27 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Lancer: "Great Humbug, The", 1968 December 31 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Mackenzie's Raiders: "Raid to San Rodrigo", 1958 November 24 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Mannix: "Search for Darrell Andrews, The", 1969 December 1 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Many Loves of Dobie Gillis: "Love Is a Science", Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Marcus Welby, M.D.: "Other Side of the Chart, The", 1969 November 28 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Meet Corliss Archer: "Corliss Plays Cupid", 1954 November 9 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Men into Space: "From Another World", 1960 January 14 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Name of the Game, The: "Lost One, The", 1969 August 20 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - O.K. Crackerby!: "Ol' Sam", 1965 September 3 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Patty Duke Show, The: "This Little Patty Went to Market", 1964 September 2 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Richard Diamond Private Detective: "Running Scared", 1959 November 20 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Ripcord: "Log-Jam", 1961 September 11 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Science Fiction Theatre: "Breakthrough", 1956 June 25 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Science Fiction Theatre: "Clock, The", 1956 May 10 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Science Fiction Theatre: "Dead Storage", 1955 June 21 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Science Fiction Theatre: "Facsimile", 1956 August 15 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Science Fiction Thedtre: "Girl with the Flaxen Hair, The", 1955 August 19 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Science Fiction Theatre: "Green Bomb, The", 1956 February 14 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Science Fiction Theatre: "Hastings Secret, The", 1955 July 14 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Science Fiction Theatre: "Hour of Nightmare", 1955 April 22 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Science Fiction Theatre: "Invention of Dr. March, The", 1956 June 11 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Science Fiction Theatre: "Magic Suitcase, The", 1956 August 22 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Science Fiction Theatre: "Marked "Danger"", 1955 April 04 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Science Fiction Theatre: "None so Blind", 1956 September 17 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Science Fiction Theatre: "100 Years from Now", 1956 March 30 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Science Fiction Theatre: "Second Skin", 1956 June 22 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Science Fiction Theatre: "Station M I N D", 1956 August 7 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Science Fiction Theatre: "Sun Gold", 1956 July 24 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Science Fiction Theatre: "Surgery on Channel 3", 1956 July 17 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Science Fiction Theatre: "Survival in Box Canyon", 1956 May 15 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Science Fiction Theatre: "Value of "G", The", 1956 August 14 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Science Fiction Theatre: "YORD", 1954 December 13 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Science Fiction Theatre: "YORD", 1954 December 17 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Sea Hunt: "Jettisoned", 1958 August 5 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - "Secret of the Incas", 1953 August 28 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 14. Sky King: "Speak No Evil", 1952 January 26 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Target: "13th Juror, The", 1958 August 7 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - "Tiger! Tiger!", 1968 July 29 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Tombstone Territory: "Frozen Assets", 1960 February 18 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Untouchables, The: "Cordial Shops, The", 1962 October 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Walt Disney: "Willie and the Yank Part II", 1965 February 8 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Waterfront: "Trial by Fire", 1955 January 6 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Wichita Town: "Fight for Thursday, The", 1959 June 15 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Wild Wild West, The: "Night of the Pistoleros", 1968 May 8 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Film Posters and Stills, 1949-1975; 2; 0.54 cubic ft.
  This series contains film posters, stills, inserts, pressbooks, and lobby cards collected by Joseph Walders. Each folder contains one poster unless otherwise stated.
  - Absent-Minded Professor, The, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Air Hostess, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Airport, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Airport 1975 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Atlantis, The Lost Continent, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Big Sleep, The, Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Birds, The, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Boot Town, Undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Bradbury, Ray, Undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Colossus: The Forbin Project, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Come September, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Conquest of Space, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Creature Walks Among Us, The, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Crowded Sky, The, Undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Dean, James (unidentified movie), Undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Dr. No, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Earthquake, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Errand Boy, The, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Fate Is the Hunter - Still, Undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Forbidden Planet, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Goldfinger - Still, Undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Great Ruppert, The, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Hellfighters, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - High and the Mighty, The, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Houdini, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Houston Story, The, Undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - In Like Flint, Undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Incredible Shrinking Man, The, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Invasion of the Body Snatchers, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Invisible Boy, The, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - It Came from Beneath the Sea, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - It Came from Outer Space, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Jaws - 2 Photographs, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Jet over the Atlantic, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Julie, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Man Who Knew Too Much, The, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Maracaibo, Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Marnie, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Mary Poppins, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Mouse Factory, The, Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Naked Jungle, The, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Oklahoma Crude, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Power, The, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Rear Window, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Revenge of the Creature, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Riders to the Stars, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Rio Bravo, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Saboteur, Undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Shaggy Dog, The, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Skyjacked - Still, Undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Strangers on a Train, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Tell Them Willie Boy Is Here, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - That Touch of Mink, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Thing, The, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - This Island Earth, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Thunder Bay, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Time Machine, The, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - To Catch a Thief, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Topaz, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Torn Curtain, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Trouble with Harry, The, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Tulsa, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - 20,060 Leagues Under the Sea, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Vertigo, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Walt Disney Studio, Undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - War of the Worlds, The, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Watch Mr. Wizard, Undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - When Worlds Collide, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Wonderful World of the Brothers Grimm, The, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - World Without End, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Wrong Man, The, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 42)